United Mine Workers of America, Legal Department records, 1909-1982 09425
Eberly Family Special Collections Library
United Mine Workers of America, Legal Department records
1909-1982
Eberly Family Special Collections Library
09425
43 Cubic feet
This collection includes correspondence and court records on cases concerning the union. There are also files on legislative matters prior to 1940.
The United Mine Workers of America formed in 1890. The union established a Legal Department in the mid-1920s.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Records less than 20 years old shall be made accessible only with the written permission of the designated representative of the donor.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series: 1: Office Files (1909-1982); 2: Appeals (1909-1980); 3: Boyle and Yablonski (1933-1981); 4: Photographs (1973).
Biographical or Historical Note
The United Mine Workers of America (UMW) formed in 1890. From the early 1900s until his death in 1939, Judge Henry Warrum served as the organization's general counsel, handling litigation, but also advising on legal aspects of legislative matters that would have an impact on the union. John L. Lewis formed Labor's Non-Partisan League in 1936, in his dual capacity as president of both the UMW and the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO). The initial purpose of the League was to support the re-election of Franklin D. Roosevelt, but it took on a broad legislative agenda, and after 1939, advice on legislative matters pertaining to the UMW transferred from the general counsel to the League (see the UMW President's Office Records).
The exact date of formation of the UMW Legal Department is unknown. Earl E. Houck became an attorney for the UMW in July 1920. By 1926, UMW documents identify him as director of the Legal Department. In mid-1961, the union appointed Harrison Combs as assistant director, to assist Houck, who reduced his duties. Houck retained his position until his death in 1968, after which, in his honor, the UMW permanently removed the title of director of the Legal Department from its office structure. Combs continued as general counsel of the UMW until at least 1981. The Legal Department and a UMW general counsel continue to operate in the twenty-first century.
General note
This collection includes correspondence and court records on cases concerning the United Mine Workers of America (UMW). There are also files on legislative matters prior to 1940.
Series 1: Offices Files includes transcripts and correspondence from trials involving the UMW and from internal hearings, 1909-1931; documents on union legal and legislative matters sent to the attention of Legal Department director Earl Houck or UMW general counsel Henry Warrum prior to Warrum's death in 1939; summaries of closed cases, 1941-1960; detailed analysis and interpretations of articles of the UMW constitution, 1941-1982; and Legal Department correspondence, subject files, and reports from the decade immediately following the internal reorganization of the UMW in 1972.
Series 2: Appeals consists of records of U.S. Circuit Court and Supreme Court appeals of cases involving the UMW, or pertaining to legal questions of special interest to the UMW, from 1909 to 1980.
Series 3: Boyle and Yablonski holds copies of documents from a constellation of related criminal and civil cases from 1969-1978. These cases involved, in overlapping ways, the murders of UMW president William A. Boyle's rival Joseph Yablonski and his wife and daughter shortly after the 1969 UMW election; challenges to that 1969 election and investigations into the prior union election of 1964, through actions initiated by Willie Blankenship, Michael Trbovich, and the Miners for Democracy; allegations of financial misdeeds in the handling of UMW health, welfare, and retirement funds; and additional related criminal and civil actions involving other individuals, including James D. Hodgson, Edward Monborne, Albert Pass, and Richard Weaver. The most significant of these cases was Blankenship v. Boyle, the ruling in which ultimately enhanced the democratic process in the selection of union leadership and reformed the union pension fund. A further set of cases concerned assertions by Trbovich of continuing financial mismanagement by Boyle's successor, Arnold Miller.
These materials are entirely textual, except for three "I'm Loyal to Boyle" buttons from the 1969 election and copies of two photographs of Pass, a defendant in the Yablonski murders, from 1973. The textual records are roughly equally weighted between photocopies and original documents. Some items were obviously collected or copied for the purpose of legal discovery, exhibits, and analysis, or to capture news coverage of the constellation of Boyle and Yablonski cases, including extensive retrospective coverage in a Philadelphia Bulletin multi-part news series of 1981. A substantial number of the original documents situated within the series clearly originated in the UMW President's Office or Secretary-Treasurer's Office and were evidently carried into the Legal Department in the course of responses to the demands of the cases. No attempt has been made to repatriate these items; they remain situated within this Boyle and Yablonski series. Because of this relocation of documents and other vagaries involving the inclusion or association of items, the original order of these documents is largely unknown.
Series 4: Photographs (2 items) consists of the original prints of the two photos of Pass. These have been transferred into cold storage for the purpose of preservation.
Related Material
The Pennsylvania State University Special Collections Library houses several other collections from the United Mine Workers. Please consult the library for additional information.
- Office files, 1
  - Labor organizations: right to refuse to allow members to use or install non-union materials, 1917; no content (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Borderland Coal Corp v. UMW, 1921; no content (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - District 2 Executive Board: suspension of Samuel Nunamaker: transcript, 1922; no content (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania v. A. R. Duespohl and Samuel Nunamaker: transcript, 1923; no content (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Fuel Co. v. UMW, 1923; no content (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Harry Fishwick case: transcript, 1930; no content (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Labor troubles in 1931 in the Harlan Coal Fields, Harlan and Bell Counties, Kentucky: report, no content (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Labor troubles in 1931 in the Harlan Coal Fields, Harlan and Bell Counties, Kentucky: transcript, no content (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
  - George L. Berry: bills sponsored as Coordinator for Industrial Cooperation, 1933-1937; no content (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bituminous coal bill: S. 1 (Guffey), 1937; no content (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Bituminous coal bill: H.R. 4661 (Snyder), 1935; no content (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bituminous coal: memo to provide for a commission, Undated; no content (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bituminous coal: H.R. 8479, 1935; no content (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bituminous coal: H.R. 12800, 1936; no content (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bituminous coal: H.R. 9100 and S. 2481, 1935-1936; no content (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bituminous coal: H.R. 4985 and Coal Mines Act, 1930-1937; no content (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bill and report of Senator Hayden, Undated (circa 1933-1935); no content (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Black-Connery Fair Labor Act, 1937; no content (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - CIO matters, 1936-1938; no content (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Compensation Act, 1936-1937; no content (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Confidential matters for discussion and release, 1935-1938; no content (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Constitution, 1934-1936; no content (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Davis-Kelly matter, 1930-1932; no content (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Fair labor standards, 1937; no content (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Fuel oil tax, 1936-1938; no content (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - General labor legislation, 1935-1936; no content (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Guffey bill: S. 1417, 1934-1937; no content (Box 2, Folder 21-24)
  - Guffey bill: S. 4668 (file 1 of 2), 1935-1937; no content (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Guffey bill: S. 4668 (file 2 of 2), 1935-1937; no content (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Senator Guffey coal matter, 1935; no content (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Senator Joseph F. Guffey, 1935-1937; no content (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Legal aspects: Guffey bill under Schechter poultry case, 1935; no content (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Wagner housing bill: S. 1685, 1937; no content (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Henry E. Jackson, 1937; no content (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Kansas Pipe Line and Gas Co., 1938-1939; no content (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - Labor conditions in the coal industry, 1937; no content (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Legal memos, 1935-1936; no content (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Addresses by John L. Lewis, 1931-1938; no content (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Revision of the National Bankruptcy Act, 1937; no content (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - National Recovery Act, 1928-1937; no content (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - Radio and other unions, 1934-1936; no content (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - W. A. Richards, 1938-1939; no content (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Rev. John A. Ryan: Organization for Social Justice, 1935; no content (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Rural Electrification Administration: John M. Carmody, 1938; no content (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Seamen legislation, 1937; no content (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Supreme Court: power of Federal court, 1932 and undated; no content (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Union Pacific Coal Co., Southern Wyoming Coal Operators Association, and UMW, 1934; no content (Box 3, Folder 22-24)
  - United Mine Workers, 1936; no content (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Letters referred Judge Henry Warrum, 1934-1937; no content (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
  - United Electric Coal Companies v. Progressive Miners of America, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Charge to the jury at the trial of Anthony Sanute, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Verbatim report in the trial of John R. Lawson and Robert McBirnie, 1909; no content (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - James M. Armstrong case: transcript, 1920; no content (Box 4, Folder 2-6)
  - Brief on behalf of the UMW before the Senate Committee on Education and Labor, re: West Virginia, Undated [circa 1921]; no content (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Queen's No. 3 Mine, Jasonville, Indiana, hearing: transcript, 1921; no content (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Clarkson Coal Mining Co., et. al., v. UMW, 1927; no content (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Clarkson Coal Mining Co., et. al.: temporary restraining order against UMW, 1927; no content (Box 4)
  - Letter re: real estate, 1929; no content (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - United Electric Coal Co., 1934; no content (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Bituminous Coal Conservation Act of 1935: brief, no content (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Joint decisions, Northern West Virginia Sub-divisional Coal Association and UMW Dist. 31, 1933-1936, circa 1937; no content (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Bonds, 1927-1963; no content (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Closed cases, 1941-1960; no content (Box 4, Folder 16-22)
  - Constitution (typescript), Undated; no content (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
  - Constitutional interpretations (copy 1, and file 1 of copy 2), Undated (circa 1964); no content (Box 4, Folder 25-27)
  - Constitutional interpretations (file 2 of copy 2), Undated (circa 1964); no content (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Constitutional interpretations, article 4 to article 20, 1941-1972; no content (Box 5, Folder 2-8)
  - Commission on constitution, article 11, section 5, 1976-1977; no content (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Constitutional interpretations, article 10 to article 13: letters from Sam Church, Jr., 1976-1982; no content (Box 5, Folder 10-16)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1966; no content (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Black lung, 1973-1978; no content (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Black lung: legislative, legal, regulatory, 1974-1976; no content (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Compensation (black lung), 1975-1977; no content (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Contract Dept., 1975-1979; no content (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Legal Dept., 1975-1979; no content (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
  - Occupational health, 1975-1977; no content (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Organizing, 1975-1979; no content (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Research, 1975-1977; no content (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Safety, 1975-1977; no content (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Secretary-Treasurer's Office, 1975-1978; no content (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Arbitration Review Board, 1977; no content (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Education, training, courses, 1975-1978; no content (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Health and Retirement Fund, 1978-1979; no content (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Mid-America Services, Ltd., 1977-1978; no content (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Penson and benefit plans, 1978-1979; no content (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - President's Commission on Coal Productivity (incl. John Woodrum biographical info), 1978; no content (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Roberts and Schaeffer Co., 1978-1979; no content (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Western organizing office, 1978-1979; no content (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - District 6: Valley Camp Coal Co. grievance, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
  - Structure of the Energy Markets, the: a Report of TVA's Antitrust Investigation of the Coal and Uranium Industries, 1977 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Structure of the Energy Markets, the: a Report of TVA's Antitrust Investigation of the Coal and Uranium Industries (update), 1979 (Box 43, Folder 2)
- Appeals, 2
  - E. C. Atkins and Co., 1947; no content (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Murder of John Baskins, Prairie Creek, Arkansas, 1914; no content (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Borderland Coal Corp., 1921-1922; no content (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
  - Cabin Creek, West Virginia: habeas corpus, 1912-1913; no content (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Carbon Fuel Co., 1923; no content (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Carbon Fuel Co., 1977-1978; no content (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
  - Carter Coal Co., Undated (circa 1935); no content (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Colorado State Supreme Court: Colorado labor wars and Ludlow massacre, 1914-1015; no content (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - Coronado Coal Co., 1920-1924; no content (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Coronado Coal Co.: transcript, brief, and argument (5 volumes), 1920; no content (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Coronado Coal Co.: transcript (3 volumes), 1923; no content (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Coronado Coal Co.: transcript, 1925; no content (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Coronado Coal Co.: transcript, 1926; no content (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Coronado Coal Co., 1919; no content (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Coronado Coal Co., 1920-1924; no content (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Dean Coal Co.; W. R. Parton Coal Co., 1967-1969; no content (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - District 50, 1968-1971; no content (Box 9, Folder 6-8)
  - Eastover Coal Co., 1974; no content (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Terry Elkhorn; District 30, 1967-1968; no content (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
  - M. F. Fetterolf Coal Co., 1952; no content (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Harry Fishwick, 1929-1930; no content (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Flame Coal Co., Co-Dee Coal Co., Amanda Coal Co., 1961-1962; no content (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Freeman Coal Mining Co., 1972-1974; no content (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Garmeada Coal Co., 1952-1953; no content (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Gateway Coal Co., 1971-1974; no content (Box 10, Folder 6-9)
  - Paul Gibbs, 1965-1966; no content (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
  - Haislip Baking Co., 1955; no content (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
  - Frank J. Hayes, 1919; no content (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Hitchman Coal and Coke Co., 1914-1917; no content (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
  - Horkstrom, Herman E., 1969; no content (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Illinois State Bar Association, 1966-1967; no content (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
  - Island Creek Coal Co., 1974; no content (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Jewell Ridge Coal Corp., 1943-1945; no content (Box 11, Folder 8-11)
  - Jones and Laughlin Steel Corp. (files 1-2 of 3), 1945-1947; no content (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
  - Jones and Laughlin Steel Corp. (file 3 of 3), 1945-1947; no content (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Cecil L. Kinty; Chester Railway, 1968-1976; no content (Box 12, Folder 2-10)
  - Laburnum Construction Co. (files 1-2 of 7), 1952-1953; no content (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
  - Laburnum Construction Co. (files 3-7 of 7), 1952-1953; no content (Box 13, Folder 1-5)
  - Laurel Branch Coal Co., 1954; no content (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
  - Love and Amos Coal Co., Osborne Mining Co. (files 1-4 of 6), 1959-1963; no content (Box 13, Folder 9-12)
  - Love and Amos Coal Co., Osborne Mining Co. (files 5-6 of 6), 1959-1963; no content (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Low Gap Coal Co., 1954; no content (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - John Mastell v. Jake Salo, Undated (circa 1917); no content (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Meadow Creek Coal Co., 1958-1959; no content (Box 14, Folder 5-8)
  - Mears Coal Co., 1969; no content (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Merchants Coal Co., 1909; no content (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Mercury Mining Co., 1953; no content (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Miles Branch Coal Co., 1959-1960; no content (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Mitchell Coal Co., 1963; no content (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Ben H. Monhollen, 1964; no content (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Nash-Finch Co. (Jack and Jill Stores), 1971-1972; no content (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Charles Nedd, 1968-1977; no content (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
  - North American Coal Corp., 1973-1974; no content (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
  - Ohio Collieries Co., 1920; no content (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Old Ben Coal Corp., 1973; no content (Box 15, Folder 9-10)
  - Peabody Coal Co., 1960; no content (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
  - Peabody Coal Co., 1973-1976; no content (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
  - James M. Pennington: Phillips Brothers Coal Co. case and appeal, 1959-1962; no content (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - James M. Pennington: Phillips Brothers Coal Co., 1961; no content (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - James M. Pennington: Phillips Brothers Coal Co. case: transcript of proceedings and John L. Lewis deposition, 1961; no content (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - James E. Pennington: joint appendix, 1961; no content (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - James E. Pennington, 1962-1968; no content (Box 17, Folder 1-6)
  - James E. Pennington: transcript, 1964; no content (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Peggs Run Coal Co., 1971-1972; no content (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Pennsylvania Mining Co., circa 1916; no content (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Perry Coal Co., 1959; no content (Box 18, Folder 3-5)
  - R. P. Price (Elkhorn Coal Co.), 1963-1964; no content (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
  - Princess Elkhorn Coal Co., 1955; no content (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
  - George Ramsey (Leon Nunley Coal Co.), 1969-1973; no content (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
  - Red Jacket Consolidated Coal and Coke Co., 1924-1927; no content (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - Ritchie Coal Co., circa 1967; no content (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
  - Riverside Coal Co., 1968; no content (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Luther Ray Rumbaugh, 1964; no content (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Frank M. Ryan, 1913; no content (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Scotia Coal Co., 1976-1978; no content (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Smitty Baker Coal Co., 1978-1980; no content (Box 20, Folder 9-10)
  - William G. Gilchrist, Jr.; Snyder and Randolph, Inc., 1960-1961; no content (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
  - Solar Fuel Co., 1972-1974; no content (Box 21, Folder 4-7)
  - South-East Coal Co. (file 1 of 3), 1969-1970; no content (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - South-East Coal Co. (files 2-3 of 3), 1969-1970; no content (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - Sunfire Coal Co., 1963; no content (Box 22, Folder 3-6)
  - Super Tire Engineering Co. v. Lloyd W. McCorkle, 1973-1974; no content (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Suver and Chaney indictment, 1951-1952; no content (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
  - Suver and Chaney cases, 1952; no content (Box 22, Folder 10-11)
  - Tennessee Consolidated Coal Co. and Grundy Mining Co. (files 1-2 of 6), 1968-1969; no content (Box 22, Folder 12-13)
  - Tennessee Consolidated Coal Co. and Grundy Mining Co. (files 3-6 of 6), 1968-1969; no content (Box 23, Folder 1-4)
  - Tennessee Products and Chemical Corp.; Basham Coal Co., 1969; no content (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - John Thomas v. Consolidation Coal Co., 1966-1968; no content (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Ray Thornbury, 1971; no content (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - UMW: captive mines case, 1950; no content (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - UMW: contempt case, 1947; no content (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - UMW: contempt case, 1950-1951; no content (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - UMW: District 31 v. National Labor Relations Board, 1960; no content (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - UMW: election: Michael Trbovich and James D. Hodgson, 1971; no content (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - UMW: election: Richard Weaver, 1973; no content (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - UMW: injunction, 1946-1947; no content (Box 24, Folder 4-5)
  - UMW: injunction, 1948-1949; no content (Box 24, Folder 6-8)
  - W. J. Usery, Jr., 1975-1976; no content (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - U.S. Steel Corp., 1970; no content (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Steel Corp. (file 1 of 2), 1971; no content (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Steel Corp. (file 2 of 2), 1971; no content (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Steel Corp., 1974; no content (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Lester Webster, 1963; no content (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Westmoreland Coal Co., 1958; no content (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - West Virginia - Pittsburgh Coal Co., 1913-1915; no content (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - White Oak Coal Co., 1963; no content (Box 25, Folder 6-7)
  - Jesse Erette Williams, 1963; no content (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Kenneth J. Yablonski, 1972; no content (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Youghiogheny and Ohio Coal Co., 1975; no content (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Amax Coal Co., 1980 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Eastern Enterprises, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 12)
- Boyle and Yablonski, 3
  - Correspondence and statements, 1943-1956; no content (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - International Executive Board meeting synopses and correspondence, 1957-1963; no content (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - James M. Pennington case documents, 1960; no content (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - UMW: official biographical sketches of William Boyle, John Owens, and John L. Lewis; articles on the union, 1960-1970; no content (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Personnel, 1963; no content (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - National Labor Relations Board case no. 5-CE-6, 1964; no content (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Tennessee Consolidated Coal Co. and Grundy Mining Co.: civil action 4178, 1967; no content (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - District 50: civil action 748-68, 1968; no content (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence re: transfers to all districts, 1969; no content (Box 26, Folder 9-10)
  - Correspondence, clippings, and conference documents, 1969-1972; no content (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Lists of local unions, 1964-1969; no content (Box 26, Folder 12-13)
  - Lists of local unions, 1970; no content (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Cancelled local unions, 1971-1972; no content (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Resolution naming the Welfare and Retirement Fund, 1968-1969; no content (Box 26, Folder 16-18)
  - Southern Labor Union, 1968-1974; no content (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Audit of UMW, 1970; no content (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Scale Committee; scale resolutions (bituminous), 1970-1971; no content (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
  - Cooperative and uncooperative pensioners and field representatives, 1972; no content (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - International Executive Board meeting, December 18, 1972: correspondence and agenda (actions declared null and void, December 22), no content (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - 1964 UMW election, 1963-1965; no content (Box 27, Folder 7-9)
  - Notice of election sent to locals by members; 1964 UMW election correspondence and clippings, no content (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - 1964 UMW election correspondence, 1964-1965; no content (Box 27, Folder 11-12)
  - 1964 UMW election; 1966 bituminous agreement; lobbyist, 1967; 1969 and 1972 UMW elections, 1964-1972; no content (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Miners for Democracy: post-election, vol. 1, 1970-1971; no content (Box 27, Folder 14-16)
  - Miners for Democracy: post-election, vol. 2, 1970-1972; no content (Box 28, Folder 1)